FADI I. DAGHER

fdagher1@gmail.com

IT professional with 13 years of experience working in systems engineering/administration and project management, including group lead for desktop engineering, technical lead for IT projects such as PC refresh, application and desktop virtualization, and application packaging/deployment. Experience designing, building, and managing different IT infrastructure components and server roles. Strong background in scripting, as well as some experience writing desktop and web applications.

TECHNOLOGY EXPERIENCE

Systems Administration: Batch and PowerShell scripts, Group Policy, Microsoft Endpoint Manager (SCCM+Intune), JAMF Pro (for Mac management), Windows Management Instrumentation, Wise and AdminStudio (for application packaging)

Security Tools: Antivirus, Application Whitelisting, Disk Encryption, Event logging and forwarding, Firewall, OS and Application Hardening, Public Key Infrastructure

Infrastructure Components: Active Directory, Azure AD, DHCP, DNS, File/Print Sharing, Hypervisors (Hyper-V, vSphere), IIS web server, SQL server

Service Management: Remedy, RSA Archer, Service-Now

Software and Web Development: C#, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Java, Python, VBA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Officer International Monetary Fund

March 2012-Present Washington, DC

- Service Manager for Desktop Engineering, supporting 6000 PCs and 200 Macs spread across offices in 130 countries.
- Technical responsibilities include: Manage operating system image lifecycle, integrate 3rd party applications on PCs; Application owner for various endpoint applications (Web Browsers, Remote Access, Endpoint Security tools, Endpoint Management tools); Build and manage a virtual PC lab environment; Tier 3 escalations.
- Other responsibilities include: Propose and present new projects to the enterprise architecture review board and to management; Review and coordinate infrastructure changes with division architects, app owners, and change management; Work with User Liaison Office to communicate changes to users; Write requirements and evaluate RFPs for IT projects; Work with software vendors and external consultants to review and/or implement new IT solutions.
- Recipient of recognition awards for various projects.

Application Packager/SCCM Administrator U.S. Department of Transportation (ActioNet Contractor)

October 2011-March 2012 Washington, DC

- Standardized application packaging methods and best practices; Built Wise Packaging Studio 7 environment; Wrote .NET application to automate the Wise package wrapper creation.
- Administered and managed 5000 workstations using Microsoft System Center Configuration Manager 2007; Packaged and deployed applications, operating system images, generated various reports and customize queries.
- Deployed file compression and encryption software throughout the organization; Built and configured policy servers and pushed the application to all endpoints.
- Recipient of Certificate of Appreciation for outstanding performance.

Desktop Integration Engineer (JPA) The World Bank Group

September 2009–September 2011 Washington, DC

- Designed and implemented application virtualization solution for 1000+ Virtual Desktop Infrastructure users based on Microsoft App-V 4.6; Setup App-V management servers for high availability (load balancing and mirrored SQL servers). VDI Infrastructure based on Hyper-V 2008 and XenDesktop 4. Sequenced applications; Supported and troubleshooted connectivity and performance issues.
- Built desktop images for 18,000+ physical and virtual PCs, used MDT 2010 for building and deploying the image, incorporating drivers, applications, windows and web browser configurations, UI customizations, and group policies. Packaged applications and wrote various PowerShell/VBScript/Batch scripts to perform different system configurations, monitoring and fixes.
- Built the enterprise image for a central bank in north Africa; Made on-site visits to gather business requirements; Trained staff for operations support and provided guidelines for deploying image on 400+ workstations.

• Recipient of SPOT award for work on workstation images.

Quality Assurance Analyst

Reliable, Effective, and Innovative (REI) Systems, Inc.

July 2009–August 2009

Herndon, VA

• Tested and validated ASP.NET code for web applications for the U.S. Department of Health; detected bugs and reported QA findings to development team.

Desktop Support Analyst

March 2008-July 2009

The World Bank Group (Ciber contractor)

Washington, DC

- •Support: Tier 1 and 2 IT support for professional staff (15,000+); supported over 100 applications in a Windows environment. Used Remedy for ticketing. Promoted to assistant Team Lead.
- •Reports and FAQs: Generated miscellaneous reports; Analyzed the support center performance and created FAQs for common IT issues publishing them on the intranet.
- •Training: Trained and evaluated new analysts and performed desk side coaching for new staff on various applications.

INDEPENDENT IT PROJECTS

Excel Macros (VBA):

October 2018-November 2018

• Write Excel Macros in Visual Basic to retrieve and analyze data from Excel worksheets.

Web/Mobile Applications:

September 2015-November 2016

• Build web and mobile applications using JavaScript frameworks (Angular 2 and React).

AWARDS

Certificate of Appreciation at International Monetary Fund

June 2017

Received for work on PC Refresh and Windows 10 project

Recognition Award at International Monetary Fund

February 2014

Received for PC Refresh project

Certificate of Appreciation at US Department of Transportation

January 2012

Received for teamwork, collaboration and initiative on Secure ZIP Project

World Bank Spot Award at World Bank

June 2011

Received for extraordinary contributions in Enterprise Desktop Platform Image creation, testing and release

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Data Analytics

Ongoing

George Washington University, GPA: 3.85/4.0

Washington, DC, USA

Master of Science, Information Systems Technology

August 2010

University of Northern Virginia, GPA: 3.9/4.0 summa cum laude

Annandale, VA, USA

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer and Communications Engineering

July 2007

Notre Dame University, GPA: 3.19/4.0

Zouk, Lebanon

CERTIFICATIONS

CISSP - Certified Information Systems Security Professional

May 2018

MCITP - Microsoft Certified IT Professional in Enterprise Desktop Administration

July 2011

CCNA - Cisco Certified Network Associate

August 2007

LANGUAGES

Fluent: English, French and Arabic